<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Books You Could Read! | Your friendly guide to the literary world.</title><description>We&apos;re here to make literature less intimidating and more accessible. Dive into our discussions that break down classic and contemporary works, demystify literary themes, and bring books to life.</description><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/</link><item><title>The Prince, by Niccolo Machiavelli</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/01-the-prince-by-niccolo-machiavelli/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/01-the-prince-by-niccolo-machiavelli/</guid><description>&apos;The Prince&apos; by Niccolo Machiavelli, the book that makes politicians shiver with both excitement and fear. Published way back in 1532, this political treatise has certainly stood the test of time. Machiavelli&apos;s ideas have seen many a spirited debate, but one thing is for sure: he has given us a framework for modern political thought that still resonates today. Whether you&apos;re interested in power, warfare or governance, there are certainly some important lessons to be learned from this Machiavellic gem.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>1984, by George Orwell</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/02-1984-by-george-orwell/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/02-1984-by-george-orwell/</guid><description>Here we are, folks. 1984. The year that saw the first ever Apple Macintosh computer and the last time America hosted the Summer Olympics in Los Angeles. But there&apos;s one event that towers above the rest: George Orwell&apos;s &apos;1984&apos; was published, and it changed literature forever. With its bleak portrayal of a future ruled by Big Brother and his omnipresent, dictatorial regime, this dystopian work has left an indelible mark on our literary landscape. So let&apos;s strap on our dystopian goggles and dig deep into the world of &apos;1984&apos;.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Great Gatsby, by F. Scott Fitzgerald</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/03-the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/03-the-great-gatsby-by-f-scott-fitzgerald/</guid><description>&apos;The Great Gatsby&apos;, a novel that has been dissected and analyzed more times than a frog in a high school biology class. But what makes this book worthy of such scrutiny? Is it the quintessential representation of the Jazz Age? Sure. Is it a powerful exploration of the American Dream? Absolutely. But let&apos;s not forget the drama, the scandal, and the glitz and glam that make this book such a delightful romp through the pages of history. So buckle up, dear readers, as we delve into the world of the 1920s and the enigmatic Jay Gatsby himself.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Alchemist, by Paulo Coelho</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/04-the-alchemist-by-paulo-coelho---copia/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/04-the-alchemist-by-paulo-coelho---copia/</guid><description>&apos;The Alchemist&apos;, the book that made millions dream of digging up their backyard in pursuit of hidden treasure. Paulo Coelho&apos;s international sensation has become a modern classic, inspiring countless readers with its philosophical musings and spiritual guidance. But let&apos;s not forget the journey of Santiago, the young shepherd with big dreams and an even bigger heart. With over 150 million copies sold, &apos;The Alchemist&apos; has certainly earned its place in the literary canon. So, let&apos;s dive in and see what insights we can find in this beloved tale.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Girl on the Train, by Paula Hawkins</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/05-the-girl-on-the-train-by-paula-hawkins/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/05-the-girl-on-the-train-by-paula-hawkins/</guid><description>&apos;The Alchemist&apos;, the book that made millions dream of digging up their backyard in pursuit of hidden treasure. Paulo Coelho&apos;s international sensation has become a modern classic, inspiring countless readers with its philosophical musings and spiritual guidance. But let&apos;s not forget the journey of Santiago, the young shepherd with big dreams and an even bigger heart. With over 150 million copies sold, &apos;The Alchemist&apos; has certainly earned its place in the literary canon. So, let&apos;s dive in and see what insights we can find in this beloved tale.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Brothers Karamazov, by Fyodor Dostoevsky</title><link>https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/06-the-brothers-karamazov-by-fyodor-dostoevsky/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://booksyoucouldread.com/books/06-the-brothers-karamazov-by-fyodor-dostoevsky/</guid><description>The Brothers Karamazov. A novel so epic in its exploration of philosophical and moral ideas that it could make even the most hardened reader want to throw themselves off a cliff. But fear not, dear reader, for I am here to guide you through the dense thicket of Dostoevsky&apos;s masterpiece. We&apos;ll explore the themes of family dysfunction, jealousy, love, and religious faith in all their glory, with occasional detours into unexpected metaphors and irreverent humour. So, buckle up and get ready for a wild ride into the heart of Russian literature.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>